[Music]
Hello everyone and welcome back
to English Pod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we
have an intermediate level lesson for you
English learners out there. That's right
on this occasion we are going on a diet
so we're trying to lose weight.
Uh oh well there's a reason behind it let's
take a look at that reason
in today's vocabulary preview.
Very cablery preview. All right so today
on vocabulary preview we have a noun and
it's a bridesmaid. A bridesmaid a
person so this is kind of like a job
but it's a short job you do it when
your friend gets married it's the person
the woman who stands next to her
friend on the friend's wedding day.
That's right and usually bridesmaids want
to lose weight because they have to get
into this dress right? That's right they
have special dresses they have to make
their friend look good they have to
match each other actually because usually
there's three or four girls they all
have to wear the same outfits it's very
stressful. Okay all right so
we're going to see what's
going on in this dialogue
and we'll be back shortly.
Oh man I've been starving myself for
days now and I haven't lost an ounce.
Are you trying to lose weight?
Yeah my friend is getting
married next month and I'm
supposed to be a bridesmaid. I have
to fit into my dress and look nice for
her wedding but I haven't lost any weight.
Look at these love handles.
You don't have to starve yourself to
lose weight. I think that's where you're
going wrong. Why if I eat less
than my body will start eating
weight my fat reserves right?
Not really. You should try to not eat
foods high in calories, salts or saturated
fats. Stay away from oily food and
artificial flavors. So you're saying that I
should eat but I should just watch what I
eat. Yes you can also try to reduce your
intake of carbohydrates and foods that are
high in cholesterol. You can have steamed
veggies or increase your protein intake
found in chicken or fish.
If I do love this you think
I can lose 20 pounds in
four weeks? Don't count on it.
All right we're back so I think there
were a lot of interesting words related to
food and to losing weight. So why don't
we take a look now at language takeaway?
Language takeaway. Okay this first phrase
in language takeaway is a phrase that the
girl says about herself. She's trying to
lose weight. She's been starving herself
or she says I've been starving myself.
All right I've been starving myself.
So to starve yourself is
to make yourself not eat.
That's right so to starve is a verb it
means to not give someone food but to starve
yourself to starve
oneself is reflexive.
I'm doing it to myself and
it means that I'm not giving
myself any food. Okay
so you're starving yourself
basically to lose weight
and she said well I've
been starving myself for days
and I haven't lost an ounce.
What is an ounce?
It's a good question
and an ounce is a kind of
weight so like a kilogram
or a gram or a pound
but an ounce is a very,
very small measurement.
Okay and this is in the
imperial system so
maybe a lot of our listeners
aren't familiar with it
but usually for example
pounds and ounces go together
just like grams and kilograms.
Exactly so I might be wrong. I
think there are 16 ounces in a pound.
Exactly. So if you think
about it a pound you say
oh I lost a pound. 16 ounces
she hasn't even lost an ounce.
That's a way to say she
hasn't lost any weight yet.
All right so she was
complaining about
not losing weight and she
said look at these love handles.
What are love handles?
I love this phrase because you
can imagine them so imagine
hugging someone and
your hands are on their waist
and maybe they
have a little extra fat.
Those are like love handles. You know
a handle is what you have on a door.
Right. You turn the handle and the
door opens but these are these are this is
fat on someone's side
so a man or a woman can
have fat on their hips and
this is called love handle.
Okay so love handles
it's a nice way of
saying that extra little fat
that people have on their sides.
Mm-hmm. All right and now talking
more specifically about words related to
food we have one that maybe
most of your familiar with calories.
Calories so calorie
is a measurement
of energy and food. Right.
And so a lot of women
and some men too like to
avoid eating many calories.
They say oh that snickers
bar that has 1,000 calories.
That's right. If
actually if you look
at your food labels it
usually says that you should
have a daily diet should include
more or less 2,000 calories.
Exactly. All right. Another thing to avoid
are saturated fats. Okay so there's fat
and they're saturated fat.
Marco what's the difference?
I have no idea. Come
on. There are two
different types of fats.
Some of them are good for
your body needs fat
right? Exactly. But saturated
fats are the ones that
are more difficult for your
body to to absorb and to
make them work for you.
So usually they accumulate
and that's why maybe
they will for example
make you a little bit better.
So a lot of sweets
have saturated fats.
Oily foods have saturated
fats. It's good to avoid those.
Right. And well stay away
from saturated fats and
artificial flavors. So
the word artificial can
be used with many
different things. It means fake.
Not natural. So you
could say you have artificial
flowers or artificial
sense. But in this case
we have artificial flavors.
That means fake flavors.
It's orange flavored
but there's no orange.
Does it never came
from an orange?
Right. You have to
be careful with these
because they use because
in many food products.
Chemicals are used. Right.
And sugars for example.
So so as you said if you
want to make something
taste like orange maybe
they will use different
chemicals and sugars to
make it taste like orange.
Exactly. The last thing we have
to avoid is this word cholesterol.
Cholesterol. Okay. So these are found for
example in eggs have a lot of cholesterol.
Or even just meats in
general like red meat.
And so people with heart
problems are told to avoid
cholesterol because it
can actually it can prevent
the blood going to your
heart. It blocks up your heart.
So cholesterol is
another bad one.
All right. So all of these
words are nouns and they're
related to dieting and
to food. So I think we
should listen to this
dialogue again and keep a look
out for these words. Oh
man. I've been starving
myself for days now and
I haven't lost an ounce.
Are you trying to
lose weight? Yeah.
My friend is getting married
next month and I'm supposed
to be a bridesmaid. I
have to fit into my dress
and look nice for her wedding
but I haven't lost any weight.
Look at these love handles.
You don't have to starve
yourself to lose weight.
I think that's where
you're going wrong.
Why if I eat less than
my body will start eating
away at my fat reserves,
right? Not really.
You should try to not
eat foods high in calories,
salts or saturated fats. Stay away
from oily food and artificial flavors.
So you're saying that I
should eat but I should
just watch what I eat.
Yes. You can also try to
reduce your intake of
carbohydrates and foods
that are high in cholesterol.
You can have steamed
veggies or increase
your protein intake found
in chicken or fish.
If I do all of this,
you think I can lose 20 pounds
in full weeks? Don't count on it.
All right. We're back.
So now we're going to
take a look at two
phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay. This first
phrase is something that the girl who is
dieting says. She says, "Are
you saying that I should eat?
" Because she's
starving herself,
but that the important
thing is that I watch what I eat.
So what does this
watch what I eat?
All right. So to watch what you eat is to
be careful of what you eat or to take care.
So it doesn't actually mean to look at your
food a lot. You don't have to stare at your
food. You just have
to be careful or to pay
attention to what you're eating.
So you should watch what you eat.
So that means pay attention.
Does it have lots of
calories? Is there a lot of
cholesterol, things
like this? Right.
For example, you may see
signs in some places that say,
watch your step. So be
careful where you're stepping.
Okay. Okay. Well,
this next phrase is the
very last phrase. The
friend says, "Do you think
I can lose 20 pounds?"
And for those of you who
use kilos, this is
about eight kilos.
That's a lot of weight. And
the answer is don't count on it.
So what does this don't
count on it? All right.
Don't count on it.
Take that as a phrase.
It basically means that
probably won't happen.
So do you think you can
count my birthday party?
No, don't count
on it. I'll be busy.
Oh, so that means he probably won't.
Marko probably won't come, right?
So that means that you shouldn't
expect it to happen because
he can't promise that it well.
Yeah. That's a good
way of putting it.
Don't expect it to happen.
So for example, don't count
on winning the lottery
anytime soon. Why not?
That's very difficult,
right? So don't count on it.
Or you can say, don't count
on this training on time.
It's always at least
a half an hour late.
Exactly. All right. So many
different examples there.
And I think we should
listen to our dialogue
for the last time. Oh
man. I've been starving
myself for days now and
I haven't lost an ounce.
Are you trying to
lose weight? Yeah.
My friend is getting married next month
and I'm supposed to be a bridesmaid.
I have to fit into my dress and
look nice for her wedding,
but I haven't lost any weight.
Look at these love handles.
You don't have to starve
yourself to lose weight.
I think that's where
you're going wrong. Why?
If I eat less, then my
body will start eating
away at my fat reserves,
right? Not really.
You should try to not
eat foods high in calories,
salts, or saturated
fats. Stay away from oily
food and artificial
flavors. So you're saying
that I should eat, but I
should just watch what I eat.
Yes. You can also try
to reduce your intake
of carbohydrates and foods
that are high in cholesterol.
You can have steamed
veggies or increase
your protein intake
found in chicken or fish.
If I do love this, you
think I can lose 20 pounds
in full weeks? Don't
count on it. All right.
We're back. So these are
some pretty healthy tips, right?
Watch what you eat
and don't starve yourself.
Absolutely. Starving
yourself, I think is
well, obviously very unhealthy is to starve
to die of starvation. That's the noun.
Not a very pretty
way to go. I've actually
also heard that people
that start to eat less,
right, to maybe just eat once a day. Their
body actually thinks that there isn't much
food around. So they
start to store up these fats
and these calories energy
instead of releasing them normally.
So instead of actually losing weight, you
actually gain weight because the moment
that you eat, your body
stores everything. Exactly.
So instead of getting
rid of those good fats,
your body stores them
with the saturated fats
and you are doing the
opposite to your body that
you should be doing. So
the best recommendation
that I've always heard is
to avoid eating too much
red meat, balance your diet
out, eat lots of fruit as well.
You have those good sugars and avoid
artificial foods. Drink a lot of water.
Drink a lot of water and exercise.
Exercise. Yeah, this is the key thing.
I think many people
rely only on dieting
or like eating less, but actually nothing
can take its place more than exercise.
And exercise is really great
because it toned those muscles.
So once you actually lose
the weight, you feel good.
You have muscles. You
have more energy and
a healthy sleep. Right.
All right. So some sound
advice here at EnglishPod.
And if you have any
other questions or doubts,
visit our website, EnglishPod.
com. And we'll
see everyone there.
Happy studies and until next time.
Bye everyone.